Richard Thompson

46 W 65th St, Apt 5D New York, NY 10023 (718) 974-9420 rthompson624@gmail.com https://rthompson.dev

Skills

Languages Front End Back End **DevOps** Cloud Infrastructure Node.js • Git / GitHub Javascript Angular Google Cloud Express Typescript React Docker • Heroku • REST API AWS SQL Vue CircleCl HTML / CSS Elixir Web sockets Jenkins

Software Experience

Software Engineer Bowery Farming

New York, NY 7/2022 - 9/2022

Bowery is a vertical farming company utilizing robotics, automation, and machine learning to optimize crop yields. I developed functionality to integrate a new harvesting machine at their flagship farm. Settings specific to the crop such as blade height and belt speed were sent to the harvester via MQTT. I wrote the back end logic in Elixir, and the front end admin screens in a combination of Vue and React.

Software Engineer Maxar Technologies New York, NY 10/2018 - 7/2022

Maxar operates satellites that provide high resolution imagery for customers such as the U.S. government and Google Maps. I worked with product managers to translate business requirements into software specifications for managing satellite operations. I built the front ends in Angular. I implemented the redux pattern (NgRx) for state management. Real-time data was delivered via web sockets, and synchronized with REST api data from back end services. I worked with the back end teams to develop the api specs for these services.

Software Engineer Freelance

New York, NY 1/2017 - 7/2022

I developed web applications using a variety of Google technology stacks and Stripe for payment processing. I created an ERC-721 compliant NFT collection on the Ethereum network and integrated with OpenSea. My portfolio is available at https://rthompson.dev.

Software Engineer SumTotal Systems, Inc.

Gainesville, FL 10/2010 - 1/2017

SumTotal provides HR software in the areas of talent management and learning. Upon hire, I served as technical lead for knowledge transfer during the acquisition of a competing product. The platform was C++, IIS web server, SQL Server, HTML, CSS, and javascript. I worked on the sustained engineering team and distinguished myself by posting the top productivity numbers for resolving defects each year at SumTotal. For large clients with performance issues I provided custom database solutions utilizing SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS). The success of the talent management product helped to create enough value in the company for acquisition by Skillsoft. Upon this acquisition I worked on a project to integrate our suite of products into a single web portal.

Software Engineer Capsys Corp

Brooklyn, NY 8/2006 - 9/2010

Capsys is a modular construction firm. Buildings are broken up into modules that are manufactured in a factory in the Brooklyn Navy Yard. The modules are then shipped to the construction site and placed into position by crane. I developed a web application to manage the manufacturing process and coordinate the activities of purchasing, production, QA, and shipping. I built the application on a platform of Ruby on Rails, Apache web server, and MySQL database. The application resolved several operational pain points by enhancing communication between departments. Through reporting tools, management gained real-time visibility into production which improved decision making.

Software Engineer CCBN

Boston, MA 6/1998 - 1/2002

I developed a SaaS product that provided investor relation content to the websites of publicly traded companies. The platform was SQL Server, ASP, and IIS web server. CCBN partnered with AOL. My role was developing technology to provide financial content to AOL's web site. The challenge for this project was providing dynamic content at static page speeds. I met this challenge through creative use of XML and XSL, technologies that were new at the time. The success of this project helped to create sufficient value to allow CCBN to be acquired by Thomson Reuters.

Other Experience

Project Manager Degrove Surveyors, Inc. Gainesville, FL 4/2004 - 7/2006

I worked at one of Degrove's newly created offices. My responsibility was hiring, training, and supervising field staff to service a growing list of construction layout projects. I handled mapping and stakeout computation using AutoCAD and other software tools.

Environmental Noise Engineer Harris Miller Miller & Hanson, Inc.

Boston, MA 6/1995 - 5/1998

I performed field work and data analysis for environmental noise impact studies of airports, highways, and railways. I developed an application in Visual Basic to process and analyze acoustical data collected by LD-870 noise monitoring devices. I travelled across the United States, Europe, and Puerto Rico performing field measurements to document baseline noise levels. I developed noise prediction models to assess the impact of proposed infrastructure projects.

Elementary School Science Teacher Colegio SEK

San José, Costa Rica 1/1994 - 12/1994

I instructed 4th grade students in the subjects of physical, biological, and earth sciences. I developed lesson plans in accordance with national requirements, organized field trips, and met with parents to discuss student academic performance.

Real Estate Agent Agatha Marple Realty Cambridge, MA 9/1991 - 12/1993

I sold real estate in the Boston metro area, I developed a client base by qualifying leads, and prospected for local listings via cold calls and door-to-door canvassing.

Education

Civil Engineering, Bachelor of Science University of Florida

Gainesville, FL 2004

Physics, Bachelor of Science Boston University

Boston, MA 1991